hello everyone this is Frankie Freitas
and welcome to another week of holotalk
for the week of May 2nd
Roberts who is our last week for coming
on the show and talking about the laser
light show convention coming up in
Canada and also giving you some tips and
explaining us how laser light shows are
put together I just walked in the door
about a half hour ago and we were down
in Atlantic City and if you happen to
travel to Atlantic City and go down by
the way of the Atlantic City Expressway
you will notice in the daytime that just
as you come in where Trump Plaza is
located right in the center of that area
there happens to be a tall maybe
five-story structure that was just built
sort of an artist's rendering of a
lighthouse
and we were wondering what this was all
about it's uh it's quite a sight in the
daytime but as we were leaving Atlantic
City
this is an amazing light sculpture which
not only contains a traditional light
show just regular flood of colored
lights and music but uh great
multi-colored laser light shows well so
if you happen to be in the Atlantic City
area and you're driving home at night
to get on the Atlantic City Expressway
down where Trump Plaza is and drive past
this structure and you'll see the laser
light show that goes on there it's
pretty neat we stopped and sat there for
about 20 minutes it's still under
construction there were guys walking
around with walkie-talkies
two of the laser modules which project
the laser images onto the structure were
functioning two of the other ones
actually had craned outside of them and
they were still being installed so once
this is finished it should be something
just a reminder before we get on to the
show the exhibit lasers and Holograms
which is coming to the Discovery Center
of Science and Technology a traveling
exhibit by Pacific Science Center is
going to run June 6th through September
13th it's located in Bethlehem
Pennsylvania so if you happen to be in
the area or close by such as New York
Philly Baltimore Washington DC
Harrisburg Scranton at the Discovery
Center is located right off of Route 22
and Route 78.
any from any of those locations it's
just a straight through there's no red
lights or anything like that until just
about two or three blocks from the
center so if you get a chance to come in
uh
stop in and say yes I'm going to be
doing some broadcasting there on June 6
for a few hours and then heading down to
Philly to complete the whole talk show
that night in Philadelphia had a
benefit down there for the Hunger
project
Our Guest next week on whole talk is
going to be Dr John Perry from
holographics North and the topic is
going to be large format holography so
if you're one of the people that writes
questions about how large can you make a
hologram that says the show to tune into
because Dr Perry is probably the king of
large format Holograms and he'll be
telling us all about what it's like to
work in a laboratory where you make a
hologram that several feet square
on Thursday nights why don't you stop by
the whole talk page and click on the
live cam link and see the show being
worked on in the studio live there's a
toll-free number that you can also call
right on the live cam page
where you can just say hello and I'll be
here taking your call so we did this
last Thursday night I want to thank uh
first named Linda and Bill for giving a
call on Thursday night and they were on
the webpage watching uh the show being
put together what I was working on was
what's coming up next which is an
interview with a gentleman whose name is
flight div Von bomb from Hamburg Germany
and there's a major holography exhibit
which is going to be in Hamburg
running beginning May 18th and running
for six weeks at the electrum Museum and
then this exhibit will begin to tour
different countries and he'd like to
bring it to the United States as well so
I spoke with flight
last week and got some information from
him and it's a very interesting show
he's an artist working with Holograms
the way a painter works with paint and a
lot of people always say that
holographic artists work with light the
way that people work with paint but
flight is actually working with the
completed Holograms and incorporating
them into his artwork and the different
exhibits that he's doing and well I'll
let flight explain it to you so let's go
to the interview with flight it's not a
very long interview and we were on for
maybe about eight minutes or so but it's
very interesting what he has to say
about the way that he's using the
Holograms and about the exhibit I want
to say hello to our friends in Germany
because they are the third largest
audience for hollow talk behind the
United States and Canada so if you're
listening from Germany hello
and don't forget to stop and see
the exhibit in Hamburg Germany which is
coming up soon May 18th that's when it
opens so let's move on to flight I'm not
going to come back after the interview's
oversaw thank you for tuning in now and
don't forget to tune in next week and if
you get a chance stop by the Holo talk
page on Thursday night and check out the
live webcam okay okay thanks for
listening to Hall talk here's the
interview with flight Biv bomb bomb
it's like you're putting a a program
together for Holograms a hologram
exhibit over there right right it's a
first and the biggest exhibition ever
made in Hamburg and Germany by one
person only well it's not just just a
normal hologram exhibition like showing
Holograms it's some kind of Arts
exhibition like a painter uses paint
um I decided to use Holograms to work
with Holograms like a painter you live
paint so Holograms and Laser techniques
are the bases of everything which is put
together and we have 12 different
subjects and each of each of the
subjects have a meaning by itself like
one subject is dedicated to the Tibet
and Hopi like the Indian tribe the whole
piece and the Buddhist yes the hotties
and so the basics are Holograms
um like um you have some kind of
embossed Holograms put together and
these embossing grams you have it on the
computer you have
United States and then you have work we
work with Canon and
have it in color then so it's beautiful
to see the different colors out of the
embossed solar bands and then
um we use different paint techniques on
it and uh well these pictures are then
enlarged and then there is um they are
cut and and then you have a well it's
two meters by two meters by two meter
and then you have inside of that you
have a laser program and
kaleidoscopes and some other things to
look at and to play with and then we
have some parts which is a multiplex
Holograms
um some multiplexerils which I work with
Peter Claudius in San Francisco yes and
he um is working on that and like we
produce them on the
oh it's like
um in Berlin three years ago
they had this um well well the Nazis
used to live and to work the high stock
which will be a parliament in a couple
of years
um
who did attack this thing and so we used
a helicopter drove around three times
and we're making a holographic lamp out
of it so we have a couple of these Works
in it and then we have one thing is
dedicated to musicians by Jerry Garcia
Johnson Polina Gene Clark of the birds
and others and then you click you can
click these pictures with the laser tin
on and then you have a computer and a CD
player in the back and then you can hear
that the he found a couple of the songs
and
um well yes and then we have Holograms
holographic pieces of art like 4 000
eyes looking out of you it's a two
meters by One meter 70 picture
um like a chess board but when you look
at it it's kind of kenographic and then
we have a part he's a swing with the 50s
50 by two well two meter 60 on three
different levels and there are about 8
500 different Holograms worth in to it
it's really fantastic I mean we did a
lot of work and then I think it's it's
fun it's really good to see that where's
the exhibit going to be held and uh when
is it going to be held well it could
start on the 18th of May in Hamburg at
the electro Museum
uh which is
the Museum of the heart Evie uh ew sorry
which is an energy
company in Hamburg and uh yes and we
will take this exhibition if it take
about six weeks and after that it will
go to other cities in Germany and I'm
working on um different kind of work
pieces of work for Tokyo on YouTube
um beginning of next year I hope to
bring it over to the states as soon as
possible if you had any plans on
bringing it to the states yeah I would
like to and I'm working with a couple
one or two of my managers to find uh
yeah just some companies and some
Partners who are trusting whom I can
work with because it's it's
a lot of work and it's a big thing I
mean big exhibition so and the pieces
one should take care of it and so you
know yeah
how many photography used in Germany if
someone were in Germany walking around
where would they see hologram
s well the thing is I started over here
about 20 years ago and I'll tell you
about until then there were about about
60 companies in Germany and 59 got
bankrupt and you have this and the
security business
um I did work for English companies like
um delaru and AHL and we did get some
orders for video protection counter
fighting this is a really good Market
but I mean I started
and I have about 14 patents on my name
and they started a fashion holographic
fashion I see and um making Holograms of
the models who were involved with the
fashion no it's like you have this um
like you have this embossed foil yes
yes and you have this on
um on a special hot minute and business
on uh on on on clothing and then you
have this on in meters and meters and
then you design it and then you have
special designs I also made hello yes I
did make a couple of
um leather designs well you will see
this on the I hope on the home page side
of the CD-ROM because the session thing
is really nice we did make about 40 50
pieces and I hope to bring this over
next year then we have a 40 50 nice good
pieces and then it's really Grand and
yes there were a couple of galleries
over here
and but most of them got bankrupt
because it's very tough to make people
understand that Holograms are not that
cheap I mean to buy but it got better in
the last years in the last two years
everything got better people making
money out of
um Holograms in
um
like selling watches or
Novelties but the main part and the main
thing is still where you really can make
money but really
really reasonable to counter fighting
and like car parts like airplane Parts
like
um well that's a hard thing we're trying
to get a deal for about 10 years now for
CD food for CD protection I see but
that's not easy
um how many Holograms do you have in
this exhibit have you had a chance to
Camp him
there are 10 different subjectives and
that will be about 40 uh pieces of work
but you can see in the in the City Rome
um there will be about 120 pieces you
see okay
um anything else you want to let the
whole talk listeners know about the show
before we close out yes I would like to
get in contact with a couple of you
people over there and maybe I have an
intern I mean I have a home page called
f l y p one
at
AOL.com okay all right well thanks for
being a guest thank you okay thank you
very much this this exhibit coming up in
Hamburg Germany in May 8th did you say
it was 18th 18th May 18th at Hamburg
Germany and they will have a web page up
and we will make sure that we have a
link to that webpage for you as soon as
I hear from flight as far as what the
address of the webpage is so flight
thank you very much for being a guest
okay thank you very much and good luck
with your exhibit in Hamburg and to get
in contact okay okay thank you bye-bye